<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Search><pages Count="58"><page Index="1"/><page Index="2"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





                    AREA III - CURRICULUM AND INSTRUCTION


               PARAMETER A – CURRICULUM AND PROGRAM OF STUDIES


               I.  SYSTEM – INPUTS AND PROCESSES


                       ➢ The Offering of the curriculum and/or program of studies is

                          endorsed  by  the  University  Academic  Affairs  Council  of


                          Deans on April 24, 2018 and passed AA-COD Resolution

                          Number  22,  series  of  2018  and  is  approved  by  the


                          University Board of Regents.



                                         BSIT Revised Curriculum





                       ➢ The curriculum is based on the CHED Memorandum Order
                          No. 25, S 2015.





                                            CMO No. 25, S 2015


















                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





               II. IMPLEMENTATION

                      ➢ The  duly  approved  courses  in  the  curriculum  is  in

                         consonance            with      CHED         standards          or     minimum
                         requirements in terms of units.






































































                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





















































































                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE
























































































                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





                      ➢ There  is  congruence  of  the  curricular  program  with  the
                         vision  and  mission  of  the  institution  and  the  goals  of  the

                         Academic Unit.

                         Vision
                         The premier university in historic Cavite recognized for excellence in
                         the  development  of  globally  competitive  and  morally  upright
                         individuals.

                         Mission
                         Cavite  State  University  shall  provide  excellent,  equitable  and
                         relevant  educational  opportunities  in  the  arts,  science  and
                         technology  through  quality  instruction  and  relevant  research  and
                         development activities.

                         It shall produce professional, skilled, and morally upright individuals
                         for global competitiveness.

                              CAMPUS
                             GOALS and            DEPARTMENT GOALS                       PROGRAM
                            OBJECTIVES               and OBJECTIVES                    OBJECTIVES
                             Provide high              Support the                     Apply knowledge
                             quality                  university’s mission             of utilization of
                             instruction in           and vision in                    both hardware
                             order to                 providing globally               and software
                             produce                                                   technologies
                             skilled, morally         competitive                      involving planning,
                             upright, and             individuals through              installing,
                             globally                 technological                    customizing,
                             competitive              advancements.                    operating,
                             graduates.                                                managing and
                                                                                       administering, and
                             Develop and              Equip students with              maintaining
                             pursue                   knowledge in the                 information
                             advance                  field of information             technology
                             research                 and computer                     infrastructure that
                             activities               technology.                      provides
                             through arts,                                             computing
                             sciences, and                                             solutions to





                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





                             technology to            Strengthen students’             address the needs
                             support                  skills through                   of an organization.
                             instruction.             research
                                                      development and                  Conduct relevant
                             Develop and              extension activities             research and
                             conduct                  that will endow their            extension
                             extension                personal and social              program activities
                             activities that          growth.                          in the field of
                             will empower                                              information
                             people and               Deliver a gender-fair            technology.
                             communities.             and gender-
                                                      sensitive aligned                Development and
                                                      instructions to                  transfer of
                                                      students aligned                 appropriate
                                                      with the university              information
                                                      goals and                        technology.
                                                      objectives.
                                                                                       Promote
                                                                                       environmental
                                                                                       conservation and
                                                                                       protection on
                                                                                       projects and
                                                                                       enterprises
                                                                                       related to
                                                                                       information
                                                                                       technology.


                                                                                       Become morally
                                                                                       upright IT
                                                                                       professionals with
                                                                                       primary or
                                                                                       secondary job
                                                                                       roles.











                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE






                      ➢ The  curriculum  was  designed,  developed,  monitored,
                         reviewed and approved by authorities concerned, including
                         the  participation  of  the  academic  community  and  the

                         stakeholders.

                              The  Cavite  State  University,  represented  by  its  President,  Dr.
                       Ruperto S. Sangalang and the local government of Trece Martires City,
                       Cavite represented by its Municipal Mayor, Mayor Melencio “Jun” De
                       Sagun signed  a memorandum  of  agreement for the  opening  of the
                       Cavite State University branch in Trece Martires City, Cavite effective
                       October 18, 2005. There are 6 courses including Bachelor of Science
                       in Information technology was initially offered for the first year courses.

                              The program was approved by the Board of Regents and gained
                       its approval on October 18, 2005 per BOR Resolution No. 41 series of
                       2005.

                              Curriculum design and development and its consequent review
                       is conducted whenever the need arises, such as based on industries’
                       needs  or  based  on  the  latest  CHED  Memorandum  Circular.  The
                       College  Academic  Council  initially  administers  it  by  comparing  the
                       existing/ old curriculum to the latest Minimum CHED Requirements. It
                       will then be endorsed to the University Academic Council Members,
                       and  then  to  the  Office  of  the  President  for  final  approval  and
                       endorsement to CHED Office of Program Standards for final approval.
                       The preparation of the full proposal followed the guidance as follows:

                              The  preparation  of  the  full  proposal  followed  the  guidance  as
                      follows:
                                 (Excepts from the CvSU Manuals of Operations)

                      Section 4. New and Revised Curricula.  Introduction of new curricula
                      and revision of the existing ones should follow the requirements and
                      guidelines  by  the  Commission  on  Higher  Education  (CHED)  per
                      Memorandum Letter dated 23 May 2001 as follows:










                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





                      A. Minor  Revisions.            The  following  documents  and  standard
                         processes  shall  be  included  in  agenda  folder  during  the  Board
                         meeting:

                         •  Resolution of the Academic Council recommending approval of
                             the proposed revision duly certified by the Board Secretary and
                             attested by the President, attaching the approved curriculum
                         •  The rationale, objectives and strategies and processes pursued
                         •  Implementation  Scheme  issued  by  the  President  notifying  all

                             concerned regarding the action of the Board
                         •  Other requirements which the Board may prescribe.

                      B. Major Revisions.         The guidelines for minor shall likewise apply in
                         case of major revisions.

                              In  addition,  a  Feasibility  Study  or  End-User  Survey  shall  be
                       prepared by the College/Campus proposing the revision.
                      Furthermore, a copy of the revised curriculum approved by the Board
                      shall  be  furnished  to  the  CHED  Regional  Office  for  Information  and
                      reference purposes.

                      C. Offering of New Programs.              The same guidelines for major and
                         minor  revisions  shall  apply  in  considering  the  offering  of  new
                         programs.

                              In addition, the following requirements shall be submitted to the
                       Board during its deliberation:

                         •  Proposed curriculum must be in accordance with the Policies and
                             Standards of the program and the CHED Memo Order No. 59, s.
                             1996, The New General Education Curriculum (GEC)

                         •  A  Feasibility  Study  should  be  conducted  based  on  the
                             assessment of community needs and viability of the program in
                             terms of: demand for the program, prospective students; existing
                             schools offering the same course within the Province of Cavite

                         •  Faculty  profile  for  the  program  applied  for,  their  educational
                             qualifications,  area  of  specialization,  subject  assignment  in





                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





                             accordance  with  their  qualifications;  employment  status;  and
                             teaching experience

                         •  List  of  University  Administrators  from  the  University  President
                             down  to  the  Department  Heads  of  the  College  proposing  the
                             course.    This  shall  include  the  educational  qualifications,
                             administrative experience, employment status, etc

                         •  List  of  academic  non-teaching  personnel  such  as  Registrar,
                             Librarian,  Guidance  Counsellor,  Researcher,  etc  and  their
                             educational  qualifications,  employment  status  and  work
                             experience


                         •  Pictures  of  all  Physical  Facilities,  including  site  and  buildings,
                             classrooms,  laboratories,  library,  medical  and  dental  health,
                             canteen, etc.

                         •  List of Library holdings (to be certified by the President).  These
                             holdings should at least be 3,000 non-friction accessional titles,
                             and at least 300 professional titles for each major program

                         •  List  of  laboratory  facilities,  equipment,  furniture,  supplies  and
                             materials classified by subject area.

                      D. Submission.  The Board Resolution approving the offering of the
                         new  programs  (s)  together  with  the  above  requirements  shall  be
                         submitted to the CHED Central Office for MIS purposes and to the
                         CHED Regional Office for information and reference purposes.

                      E. Forms.  The documents and other requirements should conform to
                         the forms provided by CHED in the above cited Memorandum Letter.

                      F. Course Number System.              In addition to the CHED requirements,
                         the  number  of  courses  in  revised  or  proposed  program  should
                         conform  to  the  course  numbering  system  being  adopted  by  the
                         University.

                      G. Phase Out Program.            A phase-out program should be anticipated
                         in the implementation of new or revised programs.





                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE






                              If the new program is designed to replace an existing curriculum,
                       the implementation should start from the incoming freshmen only and
                       the  old  curriculum  should  end  with  the  graduation  of  the  current
                       students taking it.

                              In the revised courses, the compulsory requirement for students
                       for the introduced / revised courses should start only in the year they
                       are  supposed  to  take  the  course.    In  no  case  shall  the
                       introduced/revised courses be required as back subjects for students.

                      H. Schedule of Revision/Introduction of New Courses.  Unless the
                         revision  or  introduction  of  new  required  course  is  a  mandatory
                         requirement  by  CHED,  no  revision  on  any  curriculum  of  the
                         University shall be made within five (5) years of its implementation.

                    ➢  Describe the system/s used in evaluating and improving the
                         quality of the program including:

                           the role of stakeholders

                              It  is  the  faculty  and  administrators’  duty  to  see  to  it  that  the
                              program curriculum  is  always  updated  as  per  indicated  in  the
                              latest CHED Memorandum Order.  They serve as the Curriculum
                              Committee  whose  main  function  is  to  keep  the  existing
                              curriculum be at abreast with the latest trends and conforms with
                              the memo. They will evaluate and compare the existing with the
                              suggested  curriculum  indicated  in  the  CHED  Memo  and
                              eventually conduct series of revisions until a new curriculum is
                              approved.

                           the integration of recent trends and development


                              One of the reasons to regularly conduct curriculum revision is to
                              keep updated with the recent trends and development available
                              in the country.  The Industry partners / OJT Centers are giving
                              feedbacks through the OJT students in company. They are also
                              consulted  regularly  as  to  the  latest  trends  utilized  in  their
                              company.






                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





                           the updating of course syllabi

                              Course syllabi are required to be submitted every semester by
                              the faculty handling the subjects.  It is periodically realigned and
                              revised depending on the suggested revisions indicated in the
                              CMO. Enrichment of the course content may be done, addition
                              of  more  reference  and  learning  resources,  and/  or  change  in
                              format as may be prescribed by the university (VPAA-QF-10), as
                              in the case of new OBE format.

                              Office  Memorandum  No.  07,  s.  2015  –  An  OBE  Seminar-
                              Workshop for the whole University was conducted on March 6,
                              2016 at CvSU Silang Campus, Biga, Silang Cavite from 8:00 am

                              to  4:00  pm.  All  faculty  members  attended  the  said  activity.
                              Faculty members were trained to develop OBE based syllabi.

                              In June 2020, the university formed a committee among program
                              coordinators  and  selected  faculty  members  from  different
                              colleges  and  campuses  to  unify  the  course  syllabi  in  terms  o
                              course  content,  suggested  teaching  and  learning  activities,
                              outcomes-based assessment, grading system, and references.
                              This review also incorporated the academic affairs policies and
                              guidelines in light of COVID-19 Pandemic.

                              Before  the  start  of  each  academic  year,  the  campus  holds  a
                              Teacher’s Capability activity to orient new and reorient old faculty
                              members of its content and expected learning outcomes.

                    ➢  There  is  a  system  used  to  accommodate  students  with
                        special needs.


                              Cavite  State  University  in  cooperation  with  Resources  for  the
                        Blind, Inc. conducted a Two-day Orientation and Training for higher
                        education in Support of Students with Disabilities last September 22-
                        23,  2015  at  CvSU  Hostel  Tropicana.    Some  of  the  topics  include
                        “CHED initiative on the Education of Children with Disabilities in the
                        Tertiary  Level”,  and  “Testimonies  of  Outstanding  Students  with
                        Disabilities”.







                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





                              Services for Students with Special Needs and differently-abled
                        persons are offered through and activities designed t provide equal
                        opportunities to persons with disabilities.

                         1.  The  University  takes  appropriate  steps  to  make  education
                             accessible  to  all  disabled  persons  as  stipulated  in  the  Magna
                             Carta  for  Disabled  Persons  also  known  as  RA  7277  (an  Act
                             Providing  for  the  Rehabilitation,  Self-Reliance  of  Disabled
                             Persons and their Integration into the Mainstream of Society and
                             for Other Purposes.

                         2.  Life  skills  training  such  as  conflict  management,  counselling,
                             testing referrals are implemented.

                              The Institution requires each faculty members to a lot a 2-hour
                        consultation each week aside from their regular teaching hours.  It
                        must be reflected in their schedule.  The allotted hours are utilized
                        students with special needs.  Students who are officially absents are
                        given special examinations and allow  ed to make up for the missed
                        requirements (s) during the time his/her absents.  They are required
                        to present excused letter from their guardian and must be duly signed
                        by  the  guidance  counsellor  from  Office  of  Student  Affairs  and
                        Services.





















                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





               III. OUTCOMES


                      ➢ The curriculum is responsive and relevant to the demand of
                         the times.


                                The  Institution  conducts  curriculum  revisions  every  three  (3)
                         years or whenever there is a new CHED Memorandum Order. The
                         Department of Management initiated the review of the curriculum last
                         November 14, 2017 to address the demand of times. To enhance it
                         further, other stakeholders was invited and attended the curriculum
                         review  such  as  the  students,  alumni  and  representative  from  the
                         industry.
                                Faculty members handling the subjects are required to pass the
                         revised  syllabi  to  accommodate  relevant  changes  and  demands
                         according to the latest trends.
                                All DIT faculty members revised course syllabi in all courses
                         with the following revision history.

                            Date of            Date of
                           Revision  Implementation                    Highlights of Revision
                         June 2018  First Semester,             VPAA-QF-10 Course Syllabus
                                          AY 2018-2019          Format v1.0
                                                                     1. Intended Learning Outcome
                                                                     2. Topic
                                                                     3. Mode of Delivery
                                                                     4. Outcome-based Assessment
                                                                     5. References

                         June 2020  First Semester,             VPAA-QF-10 Course Syllabus
                                          AY 2020-2021          Format v2.0
                                                                     1. Blended Learning
                                                                        Considerations
                                                                     2. Contents

                                                                     3. Teaching Learning Activities
                                                                     4. Outcome-based Assessment
                                                                     5. References






                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE






                      ➢ There is a passing average in the Licensure Examination (if
                         applicable).


                         Not Applicable for BSIT program


               IV.  BEST PRACTICES

                   ➢  The institution conducts curriculum revisions and course revisions as
                       per CHED Memo Order or whenever the need arises.

                   ➢  The institution has a Quality Management System-Quality Forms to be
                       used for the whole university system in preparing the course syllabus.


                   ➢  Faculty  members  handling  the  subjects  are  required  to  pass  the
                       revised  syllabi  to  accommodate  relevant  changes  and  demands
                       according to the latest trends.

                   ➢  The new curriculum always exceeds number of units to ensure quality
                       of the program.

                   ➢  Academic  affairs  policies  and  guidelines  in  light  of  the  COVID-19
                       pandemic were incorporated in the course syllabi.
























                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





               PARAMETER B – INSTRUCTIONAL PROCESSES,
                                          METHODOLOGIES AND LEARNING
                                          ENHANCEMENT OPPORTUNITIES


              I.  SYSTEM – INPUTS AND PROCESSES



                  ➢  There are institutional policies regarding the preparation of
                        course syllabi and other policies on instructional processes,
                        methodologies and learning opportunities.

                             Office Memorandum (Office of the President) No. 07, s. 2015 –
                             An  OBE  Seminar-Workshop  for  the  whole  University  was
                             conducted  on  March  6,  2016  at  CvSU  Silang  Campus,  Biga,
                             Silang, Cavite from 8:00 am to 4:00 pm. All faculty members were
                             required to attend the said activity.

                             There is an institutional outcome-based standard format (VPAA-
                             QF-10)  in  the  preparation  of course syllabi which was  handed
                             down  to  the  faculty  members  by  the  Bachelor  of  Science  in
                             Information Technology.

                             The format includes the revised Goals of BSIT, common grading
                             scale, policies on attendance, classroom decorum and discipline.
                             Moreover,  the  faculty  is  required  to  use  references  published
                             within  the  last  ten  years,  it  is  also  a  courage  to  list  down
                             supplementary         references,      including      results     of    faculty
                             researches.  The  revision  history  of  the  syllabus  must  also  be
                             indicated in the document.

                             Number of syllabus as one of the faculty outputs is included in the
                             IPCR of each faculty member, submission of the course syllabi in
                             all subjects handled is required.

                             It is included in the IPCR of each faculty members the submission
                             of course syllabi in all the subjects following a common format.
                             Course  content  and  references  must  be  updated  as  per
                             recommended in the CMO.






                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





                             In June 2020, the university formed a committee among program
                             coordinators  and  selected  faculty  members  from  different
                             colleges  and  campuses  to  unify  the  course  syllabi  in  terms  o
                             course  content,  suggested  teaching  and  learning  activities,
                             outcomes-based  assessment,  grading system,  and  references.
                             This review also incorporated the academic affairs policies and
                             guidelines in light of COVID-19 Pandemic.

                             There is also a series of capability building for faculty members
                             through  the  conduct  of  webinars  and  online  trainings.  Topics
                             included were teaching and learning in distance e-learning mode
                             of instruction, e-module development, CvSU LMS site use and
                             administration, migrating to online learning, and learning guide
                             preparation, and course materials development.

              II. IMPLEMENTATION


                  ➢  Major Learning Opportunities

                           Procedures adopted in the production of instructional materials.



                                       Procedures in the Production of

                                               Instructional Materials


                           Teacher-made instructional materials.

                           •  Different  Instructional  Materials  produced  by  the  faculty
                               members are submitted to the University Text Book Board to be
                               subjected for a series of reviews and eventually be approved
                               before it can utilize and reproduced.

                           •  Faculty  members  produced  workbooks  and  modules  as
                               instructional  materials  after  the  conduct  of  the  Seminar-
                               Workshop in Strengthening Instructional Materials Development
                               and submitted to the University Text Book Board for review.







                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





                           Teacher strategies used to facilitate/enrich learning
















































































                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE
















































              III. OUTCOMES


                  ➢  Course syllabi are updated and approved.
                       The  Bachelor  of  Science  in  Information  Technology  periodically
                       compile accomplished course syllabi. A copy of such compilation is
                       available  at  the  campus  specifically  at  the  Office  of  the  Campus
                       Administrator.

























                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE












































































                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE







































































                  Updated and approved Course Syllabi are properly compiled and kept at the Office of the Campus Administrator.

                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





                  ➢  Teaching strategies are efficiently and effectively used.


                              Different teaching strategies gives more motivation to students
                              to improve grades as evidenced in the grading sheets submitted
                              by the faculty at the end of each semesters.

                              Most of the graduates of the program are employed relevant to
                              the course.

                              Students  output  and  photo-documentations  of  the  different
                              strategies being used in class were presented.


                  ➢  Instructional Materials are copyrighted/patented.


                           Manual is available but not yet approved.

                           Although  most  of  the  instructional  materials  used  by  the  faculty
                           members are not copyrighted/patented, it is required that it must be
                           certified  by  the  authorities  before  it  is  utilized  in  the  respective
                           subjects.

                                                        Type of
                                                     Instructional          Date of
                       Name of Faculty                                                          Title
                                                       Material           Completion
                                                      Developed
                  1. Khenilyn P. Lewis,          Manual                   2019            CvSU Manual
                     Keno A. Villavicencio                                                for
                                                                                          Computinig
                                                                                          Students’
                                                                                          Capstone
                                                                                          Writing
                  2. Vienna Mi A. Feranil  Learning Guide                 2019            Methods of
                                                                                          Research










                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





              IV. BEST PRACTICES

                        Suggested reading and references of print and electronic resources
                        are within the last ten years.

                        Approved  syllabi  are  submitted  to  the  Office  of  the  Campus
                        Administrator per semester.

                        Recently adopted the OBE standard format.

                        The faculty prepared syllabi with comprehensive content.

                        Syllabi  contain  several  teaching  strategies  to  enrich  classroom

                        instruction.

                        All  subjects  with  laboratories  are  required  to  conduct  skills
                        demonstrations to enhance students’ performance.

                        Peer teaching is encouraged to develop students’ independence.

                        Company interviews are encouraging so that the students can acquire
                        deeper knowledge of the activities they need to perform.



























                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





               PARAMETER C – ASSESSMENT OF ACADEMIC
                                          PERFORMANCE


               I.  SYSTEM – INPUTS AND PROCESSES



                      The  institutional  has  policies  /  system  of  assessing  academic

                      performances.

                             The university imposes a general grading system in assessing
                      performances of the student as indicated in pages 34 to 35; Section 2.i,
                      Grades and Grading of the Student Handbook 2006 as approved by the
                      BOR per Resolution NO. 84, Series of 2006.

                             The University shall adopt the numerical grading system of “1.0”
                      to “5.0” where “1.0” is the highest grade and “5.0” is a failing grade. The
                      system of grading is as follows:

                                     1.0   - - - - Excellent (Highest Grade)
                                     1.25
                                     1.50  - - - - Very Good
                                     1.75
                                     2.00  - - - - Good
                                     2.25
                                     2.50  - - - -  Satisfactory
                                     2.75
                                     3.00  - - - - Passing Grade
                                     4.00  - - - - Conditional Grade. (has to be removed by taking
                                                   a removal examination either to obtain a grade of
                                                   “3.00” or slide to “5.00”)
                                     “Inc.  - - - - Grade of Incomplete. The student is passing but
                                                  has      not  completed  other  requirements  of  the
                                                  course
                                     5.0     - - - - The  student  failed  the  course.  The  numerical
                                                  grade of “5.00” must be written in red ink by the
                                                  teacher

                            Each College and Campus shall endeavor to formulate and adopt
                      a  uniform  method  or  system  of  assigning  grades  to  scores  and  the
                      assignment  of  weights  to  different  types  of  test,  requirements,




                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





                      laboratory exercises,   and the like. This should be forwarded to the
                      Vice  President  for  Academic  Affairs  for  his  review  and  corrections
                      before final adoption of the College concerned.

                              College  Deans  and  Campus  Administrators  shall  include  the
                       grading system in their orientation of new teachers and each teacher
                       should explain the grading system to his students at the start of the
                       classes each semester/term.

                              No teacher shall be allowed to adopt a grading system different
                       from the one being implemented by his College where he belongs.

                              Honor Students. Students who obtain a GPA of “1.75” to “1.51”
                              in a semester shall be listed in the Vice President for Academic
                              Affairs’ Honor Students List while those who obtain GPA of “1.5”
                              to  “1.00”  shall  be  included  in  the  Presidents’  List  of  Honor
                              Students.

                              Removal/Completion  of  Grades  of  “4.0”  and  “Inc.”  The
                              grades of “4.00” and “Inc.” may be removed through any of the
                              following:

                              Without Paying the Special Examination Fee. A grade of “4.0”
                              may be removed within one (1) year by taking the examination
                              during the regular schedule for removal examinations.

                              An “Inc.” grade may be removed by completing the requirements
                              for the subject any time within one (1) year provided that he /she
                              is currently enrolled.

                              Paying the Special Examination Fee. A grade of “4.0” may be
                              removed  by  a  special  removal  examination  administered  any
                              time upon payment of special examination fee of P10.00 per unit
                              (may be changed without prior notice) and upon presentation of
                              duly approved permit to the instructor concerned.










                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE






               II. IMPLEMENTATION


                   ➢  Evaluation measures used to ensure that the students’ performance
                       meet expected outcomes.

                                      Evaluation Measures                   Subject Where Used
                                  Paper and pencil test                All subjects
                                  Oral report                          DICT 60 and DCEE 28

                                  Research project                     ITEC 200 A and B

                   ➢  There  is  a  system  of  validating  and/or  improving  tests  and  other
                       evaluation instruments.

                              The  system  of  evaluating  student  performance  is  revised  or
                              improved once there is a revision in the course syllabus.

                                                      Department                           Campus
                       Faculty                        Chairperson                       Administrator



                       1.  The faculty develops test items and other evaluation instruments to
                          evaluate student performance.

                       2.  Tests and other evaluation instruments are then forwarded to the
                          Department Chairperson for review.

                       3.  The tests and other evaluation instruments are revised based on
                          the  suggestions  and  recommendations  made  by  the  department
                          chairperson.

                       4.  The  department  chairperson  endorses  the  tests  and  other
                          evaluation  instruments  to  the  campus  administrator  for  final
                          approval.










                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE






               III. OUTCOMES


                       Student’s academic performance is commendable.

                          Students who obtained 1.75 or better and attain a lowest grade of
                          2.50  enrolled  in  the  BSIT  program  who  were  granted  a  partial
                          scholarship  and  those  who  obtained  1.50  or  better  and  attain  a
                          lowest grade of 2.25 were granted a full academic scholarship.


                                              Academic Scholars




               IV.  BEST PRACTICES

                           Tests and other evaluation instruments are reviewed by concerned
                           authorities  before  its  administration  to  the  students  to  enhance
                           students’ learning.

                           Rubrics  assessment  is  used  to  evaluate  the  submitted
                           requirements  of  the  students  to  give  more  effective  and
                           considerable method of assessing the performance of the students.

                           Table of specifications (TOS) are required in all major summative
                           examination.

                           The  institution  implements  a  70%  passing  percentage  in  all
                           subjects  to  encourage  students  to  a  higher  quality  of  their
                           performances in the program.

                           The instructors reserve the right to use different evaluation systems
                           depending  on  the  nature  of  the  subjects;  and  these  may  be
                           improved every time the course syllabi are revised upon approval
                           of the department chairperson and campus administrator.

                           All faculty members are well trained in assessing students’ learning
                           through attending Teachers’ Capability Enhance Training which is
                           usually held before the start of school year.




                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE






               PARAMETER D – MANAGEMENT OF LEARNING

               I.  SYSTEM-INPUTS AND PROCESSES


                       The Institution implement policies on management of learning.
                           The University impose an attendance Policy as indicated in pages
                           31 to 32; Section 2.c “Class Schedule” of the Student Handbook
                           2006 as approved by the BOR per Resolution No. 84. Series of
                           2006.

                                    A student who has been absent from classes for at least two
                                    (2) consecutive meetings must obtain an excuse slip from
                                    the  Office  of  Student  Affairs  and  present  this  to  the
                                    instructor  concerned  on  the  day  when  (the  student)  he
                                    returns to class.

                                    If  a  student  has  been  absent  in  20  percent  of  the  time
                                    schedule devoted to the class without justifiable reasons,
                                    he/she  shall  be  dropped  from  the  rolls.  If  the  majority  of
                                    these  absences  are  not  excused  and  the  student’s
                                    performance is poor, he/she will receive a grade of “5.0”.

                           Different student discipline is imposed in class as indicated in the
                           course syllabi and discussed in the students at the beginning of

                           each semester.


               II. IMPLEMENTATION


                      Policies are implemented to ensure effective classroom management.

                              Classroom policies are embedded in the course syllabi. Policies

                      are discussed and disseminated during the first day of classes.

                                 maintaining classroom discipline;

                                   Classroom discipline, as clearly stated in the course syllabi,
                                   are being discussed and agreed upon between the faculty
                                   and  students  in  their  respective  classes.  An  agreement





                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





                                   certification  is  accomplished  as  a  proof  that  both  parties
                                   agreed with the said classroom discipline.


                                 monitoring student progress;

                                   Each  faculty  member  is  required  to  allot  a  2-hour
                                   consultation  time  every  week  which  can  be  used  for
                                   students’ inquiry and special concerns about the course.

                                   Students’  checklist  is  provided  to  monitor  academic
                                   progress which are used to determine subjects to be taken
                                   on a per semester basis.

                                   Each faculty member is required to give midterm grade for
                                   the students to determine their class standing in the course.


                                 developing responsibility and initiative among student;
                                   and

                                   Students are given different activities such as group works,
                                   group  dynamics  and  others  as  independent  works  and
                                   assignments  as  to  assure  development  of  their
                                   responsibilities and initiatives.

                                 enhancing the pedagogical skills of the faculty

                                   The University, through the College of Education conducts
                                   Capability Enhancement Seminar every semester to enable
                                   newly hired faculty members be trained in different teaching
                                   strategies  and  techniques  as  well  as  varied  evaluation
                                   measures for a more effective instruction.

                                   The  faculty  members  attended  seminars  on  the
                                   institutionalization  of  Outcomes  Based  Education,  TOS
                                   Preparation and Test Construction to enhance pedagogical
                                   skills.


                                                     List of Seminars Attended
                                                                 2017- 2020





                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE









                                   OBE  course  syllabus,  TOS  and  examination/test  are
                                   reviewed  and  approved  by  concerned  authorities
                                   (Chairperson and Campus Administrator).


                                                            Course Syllabus

                                                               2017 to 2020




               III.  OUTCOMES

                         Learning is efficiently and effectively managed.

                             Learning results to provide students with an improved scholastic
                             performance as evidenced in the grading sheets submitted by the
                             faculty at the end of the semester.

                             Teaching strategies are effectively used to manage learning as
                             shown in student developed projects.

































                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE























































































                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE






















































































                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE























































































                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE























































































                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE
























































































                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE




















































































                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE























































































                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE
















































               IV.  BEST PRACTICES

                       Class  policies  are  embedded  in  the  course  syllabi.  Policies  on
                       classroom       decorum,       attendance,        examination/evaluation          are
                       discussed and disseminated during the first day of class.

                       The 70% passing percentage in each subject is strictly implemented.


                       The  program  follows  the  “No  Late  Submission  Rule”  to  maintain
                       discipline among the students.

                       Faculty-student  agreement  regarding  Classroom  Discipline  are
                       conducted at the start of each semester.

                       Faculty  use transmittal  forms to  properly monitor of the students  in
                       major examinations, quizzes, attendance, and other class requirments.






                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE






               PARAMETER E – GRADUATION REQUIREMENTS

               I.  SYSTEM-INPUTS AND PROCESSES

                        There are policies on program’s academic and graduation
                        requirements.

                            Before the students can graduate, the policy on Graduations must
                            be  satisfied.  It  is  stated  in  pages  40  to  41;  Section  2.p  of  the
                            Student Handbook 2006 as approved by the BOR per Resolution
                            No.84  Series  of  2006  and  from  CvSU  Manual  of  Operations:
                            Volume 1 pages 122 to 126.

                                   The  student  shall  be  recommended  for  graduation  upon
                            satisfaction of all the academic and other requirements prescribed
                            for graduation.

                                   Two weeks after the registration for second semester, the
                            College Deans shall  submit  to  the University Registrar  a  list  of
                            tentative candidates for graduation. The University Registrar, in
                            consultation with the Deans concerned, shall review the academic
                            record of each candidate to ascertain whether any candidate in the
                            said list has any deficiency that may disqualify him from the list.


                                   If there is any question regarding a candidate, his name shall
                            not be deleted from the list of a candidates but a list to tenable
                            deficiencies shall be written below his name.

                                   Ten weeks before the end of the semester, the Registrar
                            shall  publish  a  complete  list  duly  qualified  candidates  for
                            graduation.

                                   All  candidates  for  graduation  shall  have  their  deficiencies
                            cleared  and  their  records  completed  on  or  before  the  midterm
                            examination except in those subjects in which they are currently
                            enrolled.

                                   Submission of the final grades of graduating students shall
                            be within ten working days after the final examination.




                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE






                                   A  month  before  the  scheduled  date  of  graduation,  the
                            respective  Academic  Councils  of  each  College  /  Campuses  or
                            their committees on Curriculum and Instruction shall act on the
                            status  of  graduation  students  and  endorse  to  the  University
                            Academic  Council  the  names  of  the  Students  who  are  sure  to
                            graduate and indicating the deficiencies that can be corrected by
                            graduating  students  within  reasonable  time  to  be  set  by  the
                            University Academic Council.

                                   A student shall be allowed to graduate from the University
                            upon  completion  of  at  least  one  year  of  residence  immediately
                            prior to graduation.

                                   A student who does not pay the required graduation fee shall
                            not be issued a diploma, certificate or transcript.

                                   A graduating student shall not be declared graduate from the
                            University  unless  he  attends  the  Commencement  Exercises.  A
                            graduating student may graduate in absentia upon prior request
                            for valid reason(s) addressed to the dean of the college where the
                            student will earn his degree.

                                   A  graduating  student  who  is  unable  to  attend  the
                            commencement  exercises  and  who  failed  to  file  a  request  for
                            graduation in absentia shall not be declared graduate and shall be
                            required to attend the next commencement exercises.




















                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





               II. IMPLEMENTATION

                       The program’s academic and graduation requirements are properly
                       disseminated.

                             The  University  and  the  Campus  conduct  an  annual  student

                             orientation for the new, transferees and returnees together with
                             their  guardians.  This  activity  is  administered  to  inform  the
                             concerned students and their guardians regarding the academic

                             and graduation requirements in their respective programs.

                             All  faculty  members  are  required  to  discuss  all  the  academic

                             requirements and policies to their students at the beginning of the
                             semester.


                             The  Campus  through  the  Campus  Registrar  regularly  posts
                             announcements  to  all  graduating  indicating  their  subjects  with
                             deficiencies  together  with  schedule  of  settlement  of  the  said
                             subjects.





























                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





               III. OUTCOMES

                       More than 60% of the enrolled students are able to graduate on time.












































































                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE

















































































                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE






               IV.  BEST PRACTICES

                         Graduating  students  are  required  to  accomplish  Graduation
                        Clearance as one of the requirements for graduation to ensure that
                        they  meet  all  the  requirements  and  university  obligations  for
                        graduation.
                         Graduating students are not allowed to graduate without presenting
                        an approved manuscript to their respective unit.

                         The campus conducts annual meeting with the graduating students
                        to orient them with all the activities and requirements they need to
                        accomplish before they are considered in the final list of graduation.


                         The University conducts annual Pre-Employment Seminar and Job
                        Fair to be attended and participated by the graduating students to
                        assist them in job hunting after graduation.

                         The  Department  of  Information  Technology  and  the  Office  of  the
                        Campus  Registrar  assists  BSIT  students  in  their  academic
                        deficiencies relative to their graduation.
























                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE






               PARAMETER F – ADMINISTRATIVE SUPPORT FOR
                                          EFFECTIVE INSTRUCTION

               I.  SYSTEM-INPUTS AND PROCESSES

                        There are policies on substitution or special arrangements whenever
                        a faculty is on leave or on official business/time;

                                     *Excerpts from CvSU Manual of Operations
                       (ACADEMIC AFFAIRS POLICIES AND GUIDELINES section 3, z.)

                              Make Up Classes. Faculty members who miss their classes due
                       to official functions should conduct make-up classes. Make up classes
                       should be both for extra and regular teaching assignments. Request
                       form for make-up classes are available at the Campus Administrator’s
                       Office.

                              There  are  faculty  checkers  to  monitor  the  conduct  of  classes
                       within the designated time and room of assignment.


                        There are policies on giving awards and/or recognition of faculty and
                        students with outstanding achievements; and

                                   *Excerpts from the CvSU Manual of Operations
                                                      (MERIT SYSTEM)

                       Section 12. Performance Evaluation System. Pursuant to CSC MC
                       No. 13 s. 1999, the University shall adopt its own performance
                       Evaluation system for all its personnel. This performance evaluation
                       system is designed to:
                            a.  Continuously foster improvement of employee’s performance
                                and efficiency;

                            b.  Enhance organizational effectiveness and productivity;

                            c. Provide an objective performance rating which shall serve as a
                               basis  for  incentive  and        rewards,  promotion,  training  and






                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





                               development,        personnel        sanctions      and      administrative
                               sanctions;

                            d. Provide for identification outputs and job-related behavior as
                               well  as  corresponding  performance  measures  which  shall  be
                               mutually  agreed  upon  between  supervisors  and subordinates
                               for  a  particular  appraisal  period.    The  performance  of  the
                               employee shall be evaluated on the basis of his accomplishment
                               against his performance target;

                            e.  Provide  opportunity  for  supervisors  to  make  comments  and
                               recommendations  regarding  employee’s  strengths  and
                               weaknesses which maybe instrumental in furthering his career
                               or  identifying  factors  that  may  be  impede  his  development.
                               Comments  from  supervisors  are  expected  to  facilitate  the
                               employee’s personal growth and shall be given due weight in
                               making personnel decision; and

                            f. Provide sanctions against raters who use the performance rating
                               to give undue advantage and disadvantage to people they rate.

                       The University impose an Awards for Faculty as an indicated in pages
                       129 to 130; Rule VII, Section 13.a “Awards” of the CvSU Manual of
                       Operations  2009  as  approved  by  the  Board  of  Regents  (BOR)  on
                       September 3,2009 by the BOR per Resolution No.65 Series of 2009.

                          a) Nature Award

                                    Awards  under  this  system  shall  be  monetary  or  non-
                             monetary.  The  University  President,  however,  upon  the
                             recommendation  pf  the  Merit  Increase  Incentive  Awards
                             committee  (MIIAC)  may  consider  a  faculty  member  for  both
                             monetary and non-monetary awards.

                                      1. Monetary Awards – A cash award in accordance with
                                     scales  to  be  decided  by  the  University  may  be  granted
                                     when  accomplishment  results  in  monetary  savings  and

                                     tangible  benefits,  the  amount  of  cash  award  shall  be
                                     determined on the basis of its estimated or total value or





                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





                                     benefits and in accordance with the scales established by
                                     the University.

                                             The University President is authorized to give such
                                     as awards approved by the Board of Regents. When an
                                     accomplishment  has  been  made  by  a  group,  the  in  the
                                     group shall share the award equally among themselves or
                                     in a manner agreed upon by them.

                                      2.        Service  Award  –  This  award  shall  be  granted  to
                                     faculty/ employee of the University who has completed 10
                                     or more years of continuous service to the government.

                                             Service  rendered  in  other  government  agencies
                                     reconsidered under this award provided that the faculty /
                                     employee  has  not  received  the  same  award  from  other
                                     government agencies and provided further, that he/she has
                                     rendered service for at least five (5) years in CvSU.

                                     10 and 15 years -                                Bronze service pin
                                      20 and 25 years -                                Silver service ring
                                     30,35 and 40 years -                           Gold service medallion

                                     3. Outstanding Performance Award – A cash award to
                                     be determined by the MIIAC shall be given to any faculty
                                     or  employee  who  is  chosen  on  a  University  –  wide
                                     competition  for  the  “Kabalikat”  Awards  and  Tanglaw  ng
                                     Mag-aaral  Awards”  and  the  other  awards.  This  will  be
                                     based  on  the  criteria  and  procedures  prescribed  in  the
                                     Guidelines in the Conduct of the Search for Outstanding
                                     Faculty and Employee.

                                     4. Retirement Award – In addition to the benefits normally
                                     received by retirees, faculty and employees    who will retire
                                     after serving the university for at least 25 years shall be
                                     entitled to a Retirement Benefit   amounting tp P 20,000
                                     subject to availability of funds.


                           There  is  an  approved  proposal  on  the  granting  of  honors  to
                            outstanding graduate students.



                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE






                        There  are  policies  on  supervision/monitoring  and  evaluation  of
                        faculty performance.

                               Evaluation of faculty is done semi-annually or once every semester.

                              Performance Rating
                              Performance of faculty, academic and non-academic staff shall
                              be  evaluated  with  the  use  of  prescribed  forms  twice  a  year:
                              December  and  May.  The  Dean  shall  determine  the  final
                              assessment of the performance level of the individual employee
                              using the five-point rating scale (1 to 5), 5 being the highest and
                              1, the lowest as shown below;

                              a.  Outstanding – An employee of the employee of the University
                                 shall be given this rating when the exceeds his targets by at
                                 least  30  percent.  It  represents  an  extraordinary  level  of
                                 achievement and commitment in terms of quality and time,
                                 technical  knowledge  and  skill,  ingenuity,  creativity  and
                                 initiative.  Employee  at  this  performance  level  should  have
                                 demonstrated exceptional job mastery in all major aspects of
                                 responsibility.  His  achievements  and  contributions  to  the
                                 organization are of marked excellence which his peers and
                                 supervisors recognize.

                              b.  Very Satisfactory – An employee of the University shall be
                                 given  this  rating  when  he  exceeds  the  expected
                                 output/performance by at least 15 – 29 percent but falls short
                                 of what is considered an outstanding performance.

                                 Only  employees  with  Outstanding  and  Very  Satisfactory
                                 Performance Ratings for two consecutive ratings period shall
                                 be considered for promotion.

                              c.  Satisfactory – An employee of the University shall be given
                                 this  rating  when  he  meets  the  standards  or  ordinary
                                 requirements of the duties of the position or his performance

                                 is 100 to 114 percent of the planned targets.






                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





                              d.  Unsatisfactory – An employee of the University shall be given
                                 this rating when his performance falls short of the minimum
                                 requirements but could stand improvement, or it performance
                                 is 51 to 91 percent of the target. It is expected that in the next
                                 rating period, the employee under close provision, will either
                                 improve his performance for which he shall give a satisfactory
                                 rating. Two (2) successive Unsatisfactory Ratings Shall be a
                                 ground for separation from the service.

                              e. Poor – An employee of the university shall be given this rating
                                 when he fails to meet performance requirements by 50 percent
                                 or below. A “Poor” Performances Rating shall be a ground for
                                 separation from the service.

                              Appeal from Rating

                              A  faculty/academic  or  non-academic  staff  who  expresses
                              dissatisfaction with the rating given him may appeal through the
                              duly  established  Grievance  procedure  of  the  University  within
                              fifteen (15) days after receipt of his copy of Performance Rating.
                              Failure  to  file  an  appeal  within  the  prescribed  period  shall  be
                              deemed a waiver of such right.


               II. IMPLEMENTATION


                   ➢  Concerned authorities supervise faculty performance.


                            Classroom supervisory visit is regularly done by the Department
                            Chairperson twice every semester
























                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE











































                   ➢  The faculty performance evaluation system is described as follows.

                       All  faculty  members  are  also  required  to  submit  their  Individual
                       Performance  Commitment  and  Review  (IPCR)  at  the  end  of  each
                       semester to ensure that all their targets at the specified semester were
                       met.  The  IPCR  includes  different  categories  according  to  the
                       designations and / or duties assigned to each faculty. All requirements
                       and activities are to be rated accordingly. It is used as one of the criteria
                       in assessing the performance of the faculty.


                   ➢  Strategies  to  recognize  students  with  exemplary  performance/
                       achievements are observed.

                       The University scholarship is indicated in pages 8 to 9; of the Student
                       Handbook 2006 as approved by the BOR per Resolution No. 19 Series
                       of 2005.

                       The following awards shall be given to deserving graduates:






                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





                   1.  Entrance  Scholarship  –  Valedictorian,  Salutatorians  and  Honor
                       students from recognized public and private high schools.

                   2.  A University full scholarship – This shall be given to a student with
                       GPA of 1.50 or better and attains a lowest grade of 2.50.

                   3.  A College or partial scholarship – Recipients of this award shall be
                       given with GPA of 1.75 or better and attains a lowest grade of 2.50

               List of recognition/awards given to students with exemplary academic and
               non-academic performance/achievements.

               ➢  Program outcomes are commendable in the last 3-5 years.

                       The graduates of the program are employable.

                       Most of the students have been hired in less than 6 months showing
                       the employability

               ➢  Describe the graduates’ employment pattern (e.g. employer, job taken,
                   span of time for one to get employed, etc.).

               ➢  There is a feedback mechanism from employers regarding the
                   graduates’ performance.






































                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE





















































































                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE
























































































                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE







               III. OUTCOMES

                    ➢  Faculty and students have commendable performance as a result of
                        administrative support.






































































                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE













































































                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE
















































                    ➢  Graduates of the program are employable.


                                     Graduate Employment Data



















                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[PROGRAM PERFORMANCE PROFILE






               IV.  BEST PRACTICES

                          The  performance  of  faculty  members  is  evaluated  using  the
                         prescribed  form.  Campus  administrator,  chairpersons,  peers,
                         students  and  the  ratee  evaluate  the  performance  of  faculty
                         members.

                          Students excel both in academic and non-academic performance.

                          The University has established merit system to award the faculty and
                         employees.


                          There in an established policy to handle the classes when faculty is
                         absent.





















































                      Area III: Curriculum and Instruction]]></page><page Index="58"/></pages></Search>
